Welcome to the training of EyeMusic. Every time we play a single sound and we will give you a description of it; After you recognise what is in the picture. you can go to the next picture; After a few pictures, we will test what you've learnt and if you succeed. we can go to the next training session; You can pause at any point, and then when you come back we will start again from this point; Always remember the three rules of EyeMusic:; 1. The picture scanning goes from left to right and every scan starts with a short beep.; 2. The height of the object in the picture is represented by the frequency of the sound.; 3. Different colours are represented by sounds played by different musical instruments;  Press the NEXT button if you want to start; we start with short test
Is this the letter U?
Is this the letter M?
Is the red line thicker than the blue line?
Is the red hollow rectangle open on the right?
Is the red circle in the image hollow?
Is this the word SIT?
Is the white triangle upside down (creating a form of an inverted pyramid)?
Is the red square inside the white square?
Is the white line above the red line ?  
Are these three blue downward lines
Are the two red lines of the same length? 
Is this a square within a circle?
Is this the word MY?
Is there a four lines?
Is there a white line in the picture?
Is there a blue line in the picture?
is the angle of left line steeper than right line ?
Are all the lines connected together?
Is there 5 blue lines?
Is the white square open at the bottom?
Is the blue line above the white line? 
Is this a square inside a triangle?
Is this the word NO?
Is the form at the bottom of the image a filled in red square?
Is there a red line in the picture?
Is this the word TI?
Is the hollow blue rectangle open from below?
Is the upper line thin?
Are there exactly three lines in the picture? 
Is this the letter N?
Lesson 1: white diagonal line
In this picture there is a long white diagonal line from the left lower corner to the right upper corner.; Press the CTRL button to start and stop the sound.; Once you are able to recognise what does the sound mean you can press the NEXT button (or press CTRL and ALT buttons together) to go to the next picture.
In this picture there is a  white diagonal line but it's shorter. Can you hear the difference?; Press the CTRL button to start and stop the sound.; Once you are able to recognise what does the sound mean you can press the NEXT button to go to the next picture.
In this picture there is a white diagonal line from the left upper corner to the right lower corner.; Press the CTRL button to start and stop the sound.
In this picture there is also a white diagonal line but it's shorter.
In this picture there is a very short white diagonal line going downwards.
Now we start to compare the thickness of lines.; Listen again to the long white diagonal line going from the left lower corner to the right upper corner.
Now listen to a line of the same length but this one is thicker.
And this one is even thicker.
Thicker line; going upwards, but shorter.
Thick line; going upwards, even shorter.
Listen again to the thin line of medium length, going from left upper corner to the right lower corner.
Now listen to a line of the same length but the angle of this line is steeper.
Same line, but thicker.
Same line, even thicker.
Now listen to a short diagonal going upwards.
Now same line, but thicker.
Now same line, but even thicker.
Now we will listen to a line that is less steep.; In this picture we have a long white line going upwards and it is located in the upper part of the picture.
Same line, but located in the lower part of the picture.
Long line, going downwards from left to right, in the lower part of the picture.
Same line, but in the upper part of the picture.
Now we go to two lines in one picture.; Two lines going upwards, from left to right, in the upper part of the picture.
From left to right:; One thick line going upwards and one thin line also going upwards; both in the lower part of the picture.
From left to right:; One thin line going upwards and one thick line also going upwards; both in the upper part of the picture.
From left to right:; One short thin line going downwards in the low part of the picture; and one thick line going upwards in the upper part of the picture.
One thick line, going steeply downwards and then going upwards less steeply.
One thick line, going upwards and then going downwards steeply.
A letter X, two thick lines intersecting.
Now after your training with diagonal white lines you can start the test.; In the test there are YES/ NO questions.; To go to the next lesson you need to reach at least 70% accuracy.
Is the line in the picture a diagonal line going upwards from left to right?
Is the line in this picture thicker?
Is the line in this picture steeper?
Is the line in this picture in the upper part of the picture?
Is this a single line going upwards and then downwards?
Is this long line steeper?
Is this a thin line?
Is this line going downwards?
Are these two lines of the same thickness?
Are these two lines going in the same direction?
Lesson 2: The same lines in red.; For many people, this colour sounds like pipe organs.
In this picture there is a long red diagonal line from the left lower corner to the right upper corner.
In this picture there is a very short red diagonal line going downwards.
Now we start to compare the thickness of lines.; Listen again to the long red diagonal line going from the left lower corner to the right upper corner.
Now listen to a line of the same length but this one is thicker.
Thicker line going upwards, but shorter.
Thick line going upwards, even shorter.
Listen again to the thin line of medium length; going from left upper corner to the right lower corner.
Now listen to a line of the same length but the angle of this line is steeper.
Same line, but thicker.
Same line, even thicker.
Now listen to a short diagonal going upwards.
Now same line, but thicker.
Now same line, but even thicker.
Now we will listen to a line that is less steep.; In this picture we have a long red line going upwards and it is located in the upper part of the picture.
Same line, but located in the lower part of the picture.
Long line, going downwards from left to right; in the lower part of the picture.
Same line, but in the upper part of the picture.
Now after your training with diagonal red lines you can start the test.; In the test; there are YES/ NO questions.; To go to the next lesson; you need to reach at least 70% accuracy.
Are these two lines of the same thickness?
Is the line in the picture a diagonal line going upwards from left to right?
Is this a thin line?
Is the line in this picture in the upper part of the picture?
Is this a single line going upwards and then downwards?
Is the line in this picture thicker?
Is the line in this picture steeper?
Is this line going downwards?
Is this long line steeper?
Are these two lines going in the same direction?
Lesson 3: The same lines in blue.; For many people; this colour sounds metallic.
In this picture there is a long blue diagonal line from the left lower corner to the right upper corner.
In this picture there is a  blue diagonal line but it's shorter. Can you hear the difference?
In this picture there is a blue diagonal line from the left upper corner to the right lower corner.
In this picture there is also a blue diagonal line but it's shorter.
In this picture there is a very short blue diagonal line going downwards.
Now we start to compare the thickness of lines.; Listen again to the long blue diagonal line going from the left lower corner to the right upper corner.
Now listen to a line of the same length but this one is thicker.
And this one is even thicker.
Thicker line going upwards, but shorter.
Thick line going upwards, even shorter.
Listen again to the thin line of medium length going from left upper corner to the right lower corner.
Now listen to a line of the same length but the angle of this line is steeper.
Now we will listen to a line that is less steep.; In this picture we have a long blue line going upwards and it is located in the upper part of the picture.
Long line going downwards from left to right; in the lower part of the picture.
Same line but in the upper part of the picture.
Now we go to two lines in one picture.; Two lines going upwards from left to right in the upper part of the picture.
From left to right: One thick line going upwards and one thin line also going upwards; both in the lower part of the picture.
One thick line going steeply downwards and then going upwards less steeply.
A letter X, two thick lines intersecting.
Now after your training with diagonal blue lines you can start the test.; In the test there are YES/ NO questions.; To go to the next lesson; you need to reach at least 70% accuracy.
Is there a diagonal line going upwards from left to right in the picture?
Is the line in this picture thicker?
Is the line in this picture very steeper?
Is the line in this picture in the upper part of the picture?
Is this a single line going upwards and then downwards?
Is this long line steeper?
Is this a thin line?
Is this line going downwards?
Are these two lines of the same thickness?
Are these two lines going in the same direction?
Lesson 4: In this lesson we learn about colours in EyeMusic.; EyeMusic allows us to distinguish among 3 different colours: white, red, blue.
A long white line going upwards from left to right.; For many people; this picture sounds like a chorus.
The same line in red.; For many people this colour sounds like pipe organs.
The same line in blue.; For many people this colour sounds metallic.
It is now recommended to go back to the training and try to discriminate different colours.; If you feel you have succeeded, you can start the test.
Is the line in the picture white?
Are there two blue lines in this picture?
Is the line in this picture blue?
Is the line in the picture yellow?
Is the line in the picture red?
Is the line in the picture red?
Is the lines in the picture blue?
Is the line in the picture blue?
Is the line in the picture blue?
Is the line in the picture white?
Lesson 5: In this lesson we will learn about horizontal lines.
A horizontal line in the upper part of the picture; in red.
The same red line, in the middle of the picture.
The same red line, in the lower part of the picture.
A shorter and thicker line in white; in the upper part of the picture.
The same white line in the middle of the picture.
The same white line in the lower part of the picture.
Two thin blue lines in the middle of the picture on the right.
The same lines in the lower part of the picture on the left.
The same lines in the upper part of the picture on the left.
The same lines in the upper part of the picture on the right.
Four red lines in the middle.
Three red lines in the middle.
One red line in the lower left part of the picture and one red line in the upper right part of the picture.
The same red lines but thicker.
Five white horizontal lines. Together; they create a diagonal line going downwards from left to right in the upper part of the picture.
The same five white lines in the lower part of the picture.
Six white horizontal lines. Together; they create a diagonal line going upwards from left to right in the upper part of the picture.
The same six white lines; but in the lower part of the picture.
Six white horizontal lines. Together; they create a diagonal line going downwards and then upwards from left to right.
A thin red line; connected on the right with a thick red line in the middle.
A thick red line; connected on the right with a very thick red line in the middle.
A thick red line; connected on the right with a thin red line in the middle.
A very thick red line; connected on the right with a thick red line in the middle.
Three thick blue horizontal lines that together create a diagonal line going upwards from left to right in the upper part of the picture.
The same lines in the lower part of the picture; on the left.
Three thick blue horizontal lines that together create a diagonal line going downwards from left to right in the upper left part of the picture.
The same lines in the lower part of the picture; on the left.
A test. Go ahead and test the horizontal lines!!!
Is the line in the picture white?
Are there 6 lines in the picture?
Are the lines in the picture blue?
Are the blue lines in the picture in the upper part of the picture?
Is the red thick line located on the left side of the the thin line?
Are the two red lines in the picture of the same thickness?
Is the diagonal line created by three blue lines going downwards?
Are the lines in the picture in red?
Are the two blue lines in the picture of the same thickness?
Are there only two blue lines in the picture?
Lesson 6: Now we will see multiple horizontal lines in different colours in the same picture.; Each time now you will see single lines; and then you will see lines of different colours at the same time.
A blue line in the middle of the picture; on the right.
A thick white line in the lower part of the picture; on the left.
The two lines together.
A thin red line in the lower part of the picture on the right.
A thick blue line in the lower part of the picture in the middle.
A red line; in the upper part of the picture on the left.
The three lines together.
From left to right:; A thick blue line in the middle part of the picture; a thin red line in the middle part of the picture
From left to right:; A thick blue line in the lower part of the picture; a thick blue line in the lower part of the picture
From left to right:; A red line in the upper part of the picture; and a blue line in the upper part of the picture.
A test.
Are the two lines in the picture of the same colour?
Are there three differently coloured lines in the picture?
Are the two lines in the picture thick?
Is the line on the left blue?
Are the three lines in the picture located in the middle?
Is the middle line blue?
Are the two lines in the picture of the same thickness?
Are the two lines in the picture of the same thickness?
Is the lowest line blue?
Is the highest line white?
Lesson 7: Now we can go to vertical lines.; Please pay attention to how to recognise the length of vertical lines.
A long white vertical line in the middle.
A long red vertical line in the right.
Two long blue vertical lines.
Three long blue vertical lines.
Five long red vertical lines.
Three long red vertical lines on the right.
Three long red vertical lines in the middle.
One long white vertical line in the middle.
The same line but shorter.
The same line but on the left.
Three short blue vertical lines that create a downward diagonal line from left to right.
Five short blue vertical lines that create a downward diagonal line from left to right.
Two blue short vertical lines; in the upper left part of the picture.
Two blue short vertical lines; in the lower left part of the picture.
Two white short vertical lines; in the upper right part of the picture.
Two white short vertical lines; in the lower right part of the picture.
One thick long red vertical line; in the middle.
The same line but thicker.
From left to right: One very thick red vertical line; one thick red vertical line; one thin red vertical line; one thick red vertical line; one very thick red vertical line.
Four blue thin vertical lines that increase in length from left to right and all the lines start in the lower part of the picture.
The same lines, but all the lines start from the top.
Four red thin vertical lines that increase in length from left to right and all lines start in the lower part of the picture.
The same lines, but all the lines start from the top.
Five thin red vertical lines that decrease in size, all centred in the middle.
Now a test of the vertical lines.
Are there three differently coloured lines in the picture?
Is the thicker line located on the right?
Do the three lines in the picture all differ in thickness?
Are the four lines in the picture of the same distance from the top and the bottom of the picture?
Are the four lines in the picture of the same distance from the top and the bottom of the picture?
Is there a blue line in the picture?
Are all the lines of the same length?
Is there a white line in the picture?
Is the line in the middle of the picture white?
Is there a blue line in the picture?
Lesson 8: Now that you have learnt all the diagonal, horizontal and vertical lines, we will combine them.
From left to right: One white downward diagonal line and a vertical white line.
From left to right: One short white horizontal line in the middle of the picture and a white diagonal upward line.
From left to right: One short white horizontal line in the lower part of the picture and a diagonal line going upwards more steeply.
From left to right: One short vertical red line in the middle on the left; one short vertical line in the middle on the right; and a red diagonal downward line on the right.
From left to right: One red diagonal upward line on the left; one thick red short horizontal line in the bottom part; and one red diagonal upward line on the right.
From left to right: One red diagonal downward line on the left; one short red horizontal line in the middle; and one red vertical line on the right.
From left to right: One short blue horizontal line in the top part of the picture; one blue diagonal downward line; and one blue diagonal upward line.
From left to right: One short blue vertical line in the middle left part; one blue diagonal upward line; and one blue diagonal downward line on the right.
From left to right: One blue diagonal upward line; one blue vertical line; and one blue diagonal upward line.
Now let's learn parallel lines.; A thin horizontal red line in the bottom part of the picture; in the middle.
A thin horizontal white line in the top part of the picture; slightly to the right from the center.
The two lines together.
Long thin blue line in the bottom part of the picture.
Short thin blue line in the top part of the picture.
The two lines together.
Thick white line in the bottom part of the picture.
Short thick red line in the top part of the picture.
The two lines together.
Thin blue line in the bottom part of the picture.
Thin white line in the middle; slightly to the left.
A thin red line in the top part of the picture.
All the lines together.
Thick white line in the bottom part of the picture.
Thick blue line in the middle part of the picture.
Thick red line in the top part of the picture.
All the lines together.
Two long white horizontal lines on top of each other, in the center of the picture.
Two short white horizontal lines.; One in the bottom part of the picture and slightly to the left; one in the top part of the picture and slightly to the right.
One short white horizontal line on top of one long white horizontal line in the middle of the picture.
The same white lines but thicker.
Three red horizontal lines all on top of each other; the middle line is starting slightly to the left
Three horizontal red lines all on top of each other.
The same three red  lines only thicker
Three thick horizontal lines all on top of each other; from top to bottom: blue, white, red.
Three thick horizontal lines all on top of each other; from top to bottom: white,red, blue.
Three red horizontal lines all on top of each other; the bottom line long, the one above shorter, and the one  above even shorter.
The same three lines but thicker.
Four blue horizontal lines of equal length all on top of each other; together creating a diagonal upward line from left to right.
Four blue horizontal lines of equal length all on top of each other; together creating a diagonal downward line from left to right.
Six blue horizontal lines of equal length all on top of each other; together creating a diagonal upward from left to right.
Six blue horizontal lines of equal length all on top of each other; together creating a diagonal downward from left to right.
Four blue horizontal lines of equal length all on top of each other; together creating a diagonal upward line from left to right.
The same lines; but thicker.
A short blue line in the bottom part of the picture, and one long blue line on top of the other one.
A short white line in the bottom part of the picture, and one long red line on top of the other one.
A long blue line in the middle of the picture and a short blue line above it.
A long white line in the middle of the picture and a short red line above it.
A long blue line in the top part of the picture and a short blue line above it.
A long blue line in the bottom part of the picture and a short blue line above it; on the right.
The same thing; but there is another blue line in the top left part of the picture.
Now the extra blue line is thicker.
A short yellow line in the bottom right part of the picture; above it there is a long yellow line in the centre; and on top of it there is a short yellow line to the left.
The same thing but the top left line is thicker.
The same thing but the bottom right line is thicker.
A red short line in the bottom right part of the picture; above it there is a long white line in the centre; and on top of it there is a short red line to the left.
From left to right : A long thin yellow line in the middle of the picture and a long yellow line above it; and a very short thin yellow line above a very short thin yellow line to the right.
From left to right : A long thick yellow line in the middle of the picture and a long thin yellow line above it; and a very short thick yellow line above a very short thin yellow line to the right.
And now for the final test; all types of lines.
Is the top line in the picture red?
Is the top line in the picture blue?
Is the middle line in the picture red?
Is the middle line in the picture blue?
Is the red line in the picture thick?
Is the blue line above the white line?
Is the red line above the white line?
Is the white lines above the red line?
Is the red line thicker than the white line?
Is the middle line in the picture white?
Lesson 9: Now we will learn about shapes.; Overall it should not be very difficult because the shapes are created by lines that you've already learned.; First we will learn about squares and we will build them from lines.
A vertical thin red line on the left of the picture.
A vertical thin red line on the left side of the picture with a thin red line to the right of the picture.
A thin red horizontal line at the bottom of the picture.
A thin red horizontal line at the bottom of the picture with a thin red horizontal line at the top of the picture.
Angle: A thin red horizontal line that is connected on the right with a thin red vertical line.
Left to right: A red vertical line; a red horizontal line at the bottom of the picture; and a red vertical line that together create a box open from the top.
Left to right: A red vertical line; a red horizontal line at the top of the picture; and a red vertical line that together create a box open from the bottom.
Left to right: A red horizontal line at the bottom; a red horizontal line at the top; and a red vertical line in the middle right; together they form a box open to the left.
Left to right: A red horizontal line at the bottom; a red horizontal line at the top; and a red vertical line in the middle left together they form a box open to the right.
A hollow square made of red thin lines.
A filled in red square.
A white box open to the top.
A white box open to the right.
A white box open to the left.
A hollow white square.
A small hollow white square.
A filled in white square.
A small filled in white square.
A filled in blue square.
A small hollow blue square.
A long hollow horizontal white rectangle at the top of the image.
The same rectangle, but thicker lines.
A hollow vertical blue rectangle.
A filled in vertical blue rectangle.
A hollow vertical blue rectangle.
A filled in vertical blue rectangle.
A hollow vertical white rectangle.
A filled in vertical white rectangle.
A hollow vertical red rectangle.
A filled in vertical red rectangle.
A rising diagonal red line at the bottom of the image.
A descending diagonal red line at the bottom of the image
A red horizontal line at the bottom of the image.
The three lines together form a red triangle.
A hollow red triangle without the descending diagonal line.
A short rising diagonal white line at the top of the image.
A short descending diagonal white line at the top of the image.
A horizontal white line at the top of the image.
The three lines together form a hollow white triangle (an inverted pyramid) at the top of the image.
A hollow white triangle at the top of the image without the descending diagonal line.
A hollow blue triangle at the bottom of the image.
A filled in blue triangle at the bottom of the image.
A hollow blue triangle at the bottom of the image.
A filled in blue triangle at the bottom of the image.
A hollow red triangle at the bottom of the image.
A filled in red triangle at the bottom of the image.
Now let's draw a circle: This picture has a blue line that rises and then falls; creating a top half of a circle.
This picture has a blue line that falls and then rises; creating the lower half of the circle.
The two lines together form a hollow blue circle.
The upper half of a filled in blue circle.
The lower half of a filled in blue circle.
A filled in blue circle.
The left half of a red hollow circle.
The right half of a red hollow circle.
A hollow red circle.
The left half of a full circle in blue.
The right half of full circle in blue.
A filled in blue circle.
Now we will study shapes within shapes.; In this picture you can hear a little hollow blue square next to a large blue hollow square.
In this picture the little hollow blue square is inside in the large blue square.
A small hollow red square inside a large hollow red square.
A small red hollow square inside a large white hollow square.
A small blue hollow triangle inside a large blue hollow triangle.
A small filled in red square inside a large hollow blue triangle.
A small filled in white square inside a large hollow blue triangle.
A filled in small white square inside a large hollow blue circle.
Final exam; you have 30 questions at 15 minutes; good luck
Is the white triangle upside down (creating a form of an inverted pyramid)?
Is the red circle in the image hollow?
Is the red square inside the white square?
Is the hollow blue rectangle open from below?
Is the red hollow rectangle open on the right?
Is the upper line thin?
Is the white square open at the bottom?
Is this a square within a circle?
Is this a square inside a triangle?
Is the form at the bottom of the image a filled in red square?
Is there a four lines?
Is this the word NO?
is the angle of left line steeper than right line ?
Is this the word SIT?
Is the white line above the red line ?  
Is there a white line in the picture?
Is there a blue line in the picture?
Is there a red line in the picture?
Is this the word TI?
Is this the word MY?
Are there exactly three lines in the picture? 
Is this the letter U?
Is this the letter M?
Is the red line thicker than the blue line?
Is this the letter N?
Is the blue line above the white line? 
Are all the lines connected together?
Is there 5 blue lines?
Are these three blue downward lines
Are the two red lines of the same length? 
Thanks , now please fill a short feedback 
